<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>^^</title>
    <link>https://aneesahammed.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on ^^</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 03 May 2019 23:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://aneesahammed.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Daily log</title>
      <link>https://aneesahammed.github.io/posts/daily-log/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 May 2019 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aneesahammed.github.io/posts/daily-log/</guid>
      <description>For me, it is so important to keep track of my daily tasks I do at work. And there are loads of tools available to help you do that.
However most of the time, on your work machine/ office laptop, you do not have the privilege to install the tool of your choice.
So here, I just wanted to share a little-known simple &amp;amp; neat trick, that I have been using more than a decade successfully which is built right into the Window’s default Notepad app.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GitHub Auto Tagger</title>
      <link>https://aneesahammed.github.io/posts/github-auto-tagger/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Apr 2019 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aneesahammed.github.io/posts/github-auto-tagger/</guid>
      <description>I keep track of all my work using GitHub project boards.
To simplify, automate &amp;amp; improve my GitHub issue management workflow therefore to scratch my own itch, I made simple GitHub Probot app autotagger. It automatically tags GitHub Issues based on the matched pattern. Simply mention your tags in square brackets [&amp;hellip;] on Issue title.
Please install autotagger, I&amp;rsquo;d love to hear your feedback. You can find more details about the Probot from here.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>RabbitMQ</title>
      <link>https://aneesahammed.github.io/posts/rabbitmq/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Nov 2018 11:36:55 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aneesahammed.github.io/posts/rabbitmq/</guid>
      <description>_______________ &amp;lt; Im not rabbit!! &amp;gt; --------------- \ ^__^ \ (oo)\_______ (__)\ )\/\ ||----w | || ||  Today at work, in order to demonstrate a proof of concept (POC) related to message queues, had to spin up a rabbitmq server. &amp;ldquo;Play with Docker&amp;rdquo; come to the rescue. In couple of minutes environment is up and ready.
docker run -d \ --hostname rabbit-host \ --name rabbit-container \ -p 80:15672 \ -p 5672:5672 \ -e RABBITMQ_DEFAULT_USER=&amp;quot;rabbit&amp;quot; \ -e RABBITMQ_DEFAULT_PASS=&amp;quot;carrot&amp;quot; \ rabbitmq:3-management     PORT Description     15672 RabbitMQ Management console uses PORT 15672 for RabbitMQ version 3.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Play with docker</title>
      <link>https://aneesahammed.github.io/posts/play-with-docker/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Oct 2018 11:36:55 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aneesahammed.github.io/posts/play-with-docker/</guid>
      <description>Prerequisite Make sure you have already created a Docker Hub account.
PWD This post is about &amp;ldquo;Play with Docker&amp;rdquo; chrome-extension. Play with Docker(PWD) by itself is a simple, interactive and fun playground to learn Docker. This will give you a throwaway *nix shell, in which you can safely play with docker.

Extension adds a &amp;ldquo;Try in PWD&amp;rdquo; button on any Docker Hub image page. Here is a short demo of same.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CURL</title>
      <link>https://aneesahammed.github.io/posts/curl/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Oct 2018 11:36:55 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aneesahammed.github.io/posts/curl/</guid>
      <description>As part of my journey as a developer and decision to document my learning, I&amp;rsquo;ve been thinking of writing a short post regarding curl, here it is.
Curl is a command line tool for transferring data to and from a server. Curl stands for Client URL and was developed by a Swedish developer Daniel Stenberg @bagder.
It covers many protocols like HTTP, FTP, IMAP, POP3 &amp;amp; SMTP, It usually comes pre-installed in most of Linux distros and modern versions of OS X.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ഐറിഷ് ബ്രേക്‌ഫാസ്റ്</title>
      <link>https://aneesahammed.github.io/posts/irish-breakfast/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Oct 2017 11:36:55 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aneesahammed.github.io/posts/irish-breakfast/</guid>
      <description>ഐറിഷ് ബ്രേക്‌ഫാസ്റ്
സൂര്യൻ ഉദിച്ചെന്നു ഉറപ്പു വരുത്തി, ഇന്നലെ രാത്രി ഗൂഗിൾ തിരച്ചിലിൽ നിന്നും കണ്ടു വച്ച &amp;lsquo;മസാല&amp;rsquo; എന്ന ഇന്ത്യൻ ഹോട്ടലും തേടി ഇറങ്ങി. ചെറിയ മഴ ചാറലും കാറ്റും ഉണ്ട് .
കാലാവസ്ഥ മാറാൻ തുടങ്ങി ഇരിക്കുന്നു. അതൊന്നും വക വെക്കാതെ, നല്ല മസാല ദോശയും ഫിൽറ്റർ കോഫിയും സ്വപ്നം കണ്ടു വായിൽ കപ്പൽ ഓടിക്കാനുള്ള വെള്ളവും, വയറ്റിലെ ഗുളു ഗുളു ശബ്ദവും ഒക്കെ ആയി, ഹോട്ടലിനടുത്തെത്തിയപ്പോഴാണ് മനസ്സിലായത്, ഇവിടെ മിക്ക ഹോട്ടലുകളും വൈകീട്ടു 5 നു മാത്രമേ തുറക്കൂ എന്ന് .
വിശന്നു വിഷണ്ണനായി റൂമിൽ തിരികെ വന്നു. എന്തായാലും ഇന്ന് വല്ലതും കഴിച്ചിട്ട് തന്നെ എന്നുറപ്പിച്ചു ഹോട്ടൽ റെസ്റ്റാറ്റാന്റിലേക്ക്‌ വിളിച്ചു, രണ്ടു തരം ഭക്ഷണമാണുള്ളത് കോണ്ടിനെന്റൽ &amp;amp; ഫുൾ ഐറിഷ് ബ്രേക്‌ഫാസ്റ്.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rapid Prototyping</title>
      <link>https://aneesahammed.github.io/posts/rapid-prototype/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Aug 2017 11:36:55 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aneesahammed.github.io/posts/rapid-prototype/</guid>
      <description>This is to document my last remote consulting experience for a Mobile Application.
In order to get clarity in design, we often go through a prototype phase. This is an important phase as this allows you to refine the user experience.
Although there are a huge number of tools out there that are dedicated solely to prototyping. I&amp;rsquo;ve seen effective prototypes made with PowerPoint, Keynote, Acrobat, and Word. If you&amp;rsquo;re a designer and have skills in programs like high-end graphic software like Sketch.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>XAML Styler for Visual Studio Mac</title>
      <link>https://aneesahammed.github.io/posts/xaml-styler/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Aug 2017 11:36:55 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aneesahammed.github.io/posts/xaml-styler/</guid>
      <description>If you have already worked on WPF or Windows Phone projects, you might have used the XAML Styler. Which is a visual studio extension for formatting XAML source code, which helps in maintaining better XAML coding style and better XAML readability.
I have been using this extension for quite some time including my Xamarin Forms projects in Xamarin Studio. Even though “Visual Studio for Mac” was available, I remained with Xamarin Studio as XAML Styler was not supported in VS for MAC.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Working with Microsoft</title>
      <link>https://aneesahammed.github.io/posts/microsoft/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Aug 2017 11:36:55 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aneesahammed.github.io/posts/microsoft/</guid>
      <description>A couple of months back I got invited to work with Microsoft Middle East, Dubai  to port the glimpses win32 app into Microsoft Store.
It was really important for us to be able to take advantage of the best that windows 10 has to offer without rebuilding the glimpses app.
Desktop Bridge provided the perfect solution for us to be able to keep all the work we’ve done before and embrace future, it is an obvious choice for us to give a more trustworthy source to users.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Best way to record your screen on Android!!!</title>
      <link>https://aneesahammed.github.io/posts/record-android-screen/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Jun 2017 11:36:55 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aneesahammed.github.io/posts/record-android-screen/</guid>
      <description>If you wanted to record a tutorial or wanted to create a demo of your app you&amp;rsquo;d need to capture the screen in real time. Without installing some third-party crappy piece of software this is daunting. So below is one of the easy steps to follow for geeks in you.
Download the platform-tools from below URL if you don&amp;rsquo;t have Android Studio installed.
developer.android.com  Connect your Android Phone to your computer.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hello World</title>
      <link>https://aneesahammed.github.io/posts/hello-world/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 May 2017 11:36:55 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aneesahammed.github.io/posts/hello-world/</guid>
      <description>&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-shell&#34;&gt;_____________
&amp;lt; Hello World &amp;gt;
 -------------
        \   ^__^
         \  (oo)\_______
            (__)\       )\/\
                ||----w |
                ||     ||
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hello, World!! I have been wanting to start my own blog hosted on github.io for a while now.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>